# **Darryl Dixon**

Newport News, Virginia <a href="http://PieceDigital.github.io">http://PieceDigital.github.io</a> <a href="http://github.com/PieceDigital">http://github.com/PieceDigital</a> PieceDigitalStudios@gmail.com

## **Summary**

I'm a self-educated web developer with a passion for building websites and web applications with great user experience. I specialize in improving user experience by improving user interfaces and optimising code, which results in greater user retention.

#### Skills

- Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (client- and server-side)
- JavaScript Libraries and Frameworks: jQuery, ReactJS, AngularJS(basic), ExpressJS, Socket.io
- Tools: Photoshop, Git (and GitHub), Gulp, Handlebars.js, Sass
- Others: Responsive Design, Mentoring

## **Experience**

#### **Web Application Developer**

Guide Magazine

Aug 2015 - Oct 2015

- Created a fully featured JavaScript chat application, complete with admin panel: http://piecedigital.github.io/gcc-app
- Designed the app to be touchscreen-friendly and responsive across desktop and mobile
- Constructed server code to be modular and efficient

#### Web Developer/Consultant

MTM Landscaping

Mar 2015 - May 2015

- Assisted in design decisions
  - Constructed web code for optimal load times

#### Web Designer/Developer

Meraki Natural Hair

Oct 2014 - May 2015

- Designed the website to be aesthetically comfortable and pleasing, using wireframes and mockup as guides for implementation
- Constructed web code to be manageable and efficient

### **Education**

Free Code Camp Oct 2014 - Apr 2015

• Completed this online curriculum in 6 months, where I learned my skills in full-stack web development. <a href="http://FreeCodeCamp.com/">http://FreeCodeCamp.com/</a>

CodeCademy Oct 2014 - Apr 2015

• A general online course where I learned the essentials of web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)